Guide to the Gerald Kaufman Papers, 1969-1972 AIS.1972.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Gerald Kaufman Papers
1969-1972
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Kaufman, Gerald
AIS.1972.15
4.38 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
This collection contains correspondence, memorandums, speeches, notes, reports, newspaper clippings, pamphlets of Pennsylvania state legislator, Gerald Kaufman.
Biography
Born in 1932, the Honorable Gerald Kaufman was state Representative of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania who served three terms in the House where he was known for being a 'champion of liberal and consumer legislation'. Kaufman, who was from Squirrel Hill, was a political figure actively involved in the General Assembly serving on a number of committees including such issues as industrial development, education, health and welfare and was chairman of the Welfare Subcommittee of the Appropriations Committee. He gave many speeches during his tenure which are included in this collections as well as constituents repsonses. Kaufman's career covered the time period from 1969 to 1972.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes correspondence, memoranda, speeches, notes, reports, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets. These materials are organized in a total of 9 boxes under one series and 103 folders. Such subjects as the following make up this collection: abortion; busing; insurance premiums; Labor Relations Committee; medical assistance; mental health office reorganization; mental retardation; nursing homes; personal propperty tax; primary election; public employees collective bargaining bill; public employees legislation; retired teachers' income; "Right to Work" Law; scholarship program; state income tax; students' rights; tax and budget problems; unemployment compensation; Uniform Anatomical Gift Act; and youth development centers.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Honorable Gerald Kaufman December 12,1972
Previous Citation
Gerald Kaufman Papers, 1969-1972, AIS.1972.15, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Income tax -- Pennsylvania; Legislators; Slums -- Pennsylvania; Women's rights -- Pennsylvania; Politics; Personal papers; Legislators -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Women; Abortion -- Pennsylvania; Busing for school integration -- Pennsylvania; Child welfare -- Pennsylvania; Insurance, No fault automobile -- Pennsylvania; Kaufman, Gerald
- Abortion, I.
  - Abortion Bill, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Governors Commission on Abortion (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abortion Information (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, II.
  - In favor of abortion, Pt. 1 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - In favor of abortion, Pt.2 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Against abortion (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Adoption, Pt.1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Adoption, Pt.2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Air pollution (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Amendments, III.
  - Birth registration (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - H.B. 526 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - H.B.2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - S.B.954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - State Retirement Code (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Congratulatory Messages (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Construction Trade Unions (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Education, IV.
  - Busing Bills (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chatham College (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Educational Voucher Project (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Harrisburgh Area Community College (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Integration of Professional Staffs in Public Schools (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Libraries (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Lunch Programs (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pittsburgh School Board (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Psychology-Licensure (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Safety Regulation for School Buses (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - School District Records Open Bill (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - School Suspension (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Teacher's Retirement Bill (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - University of Pa. -S.B. 1126 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - University of Pittsburgh (Expansion Plans) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Ethics Committee Ruling (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Fan Mail and Publicity (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Flags and Manuals of Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Food and Hunger-White House Committee (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Form Letter Responses to Constituents (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Government, V.
  - Administrative Code of 1929 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Governor's Office (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Legislative Modernization (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - House Rules Changes (Box 5, Folder 45)
- House Bills, VI.
  - Appropriations Committee (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Health Welfare Committee (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Specific Bills-Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Juveniles, VII.
  - Detention for Juveniles (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Information-"Task Force on Juveniles" (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Juvenile Commitment Bills (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Advisory Council (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Senate Bill 439 (Juvenile Act) (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Commonwealth Youth Confernence (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Warrendale Youth Development Center (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Youth Development Center Questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - McGovern (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Mental Health, VIII.
  - Appropriations Committee (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Appropriations Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Community MH/MR Task Force (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Dept. of Health Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Development Disabilities Advisory Council (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Disabilities Planning Advisory Council (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - House Bill No. 792 (Special Education) (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - House Bill 1145 (MH Commissioner) (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Institutional Peonage (H.B.1141) (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Memo-Alert (Reorganization MH/MR), September 17, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Right to Treatment (H.B.1142) (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - State Institutions (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, July 1972 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - No-Fault Insurance (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Nuclear Explosions-Operation "Ketch" (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Nursing Homes (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Protective Lenses (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Public Employees (H.B. 1443) (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - requests and Favors Done (Box 7, Folder 79-80)
  - Resolution (H.B. 210 Income Maintenance Program) (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Roll Call-1971-72 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Salary Commission, Creation of (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Legislative Salary Increase, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Slum Housing Dwelling Inspection (Box 8, Folder 85)
- Taxes, IX.
  - Multi-State Tax Compact (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Personal Income Tax Information (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Personal Property Tax Bills (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Senior Citizens Property Tax (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Tractor-Trailer Bill (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Unemployment Compensation Law (Box 9, Folder 91)
- Vietnam, X.
  - Vietnam Compensation (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Vietnam Conflict Bonus (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Vietnam House Resolutions #53 (Box 9, Folder 94)
- Welfare, XI.
  - Child Welfare (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Federal Welfare (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Human Services (House Reg.177) (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Medical Assistance (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Regionalization Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Reorganization of Welfare (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Welfare Planning Council-Scranton (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - United Family Services of Pittsburgh, Inc. (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Women's Liberation (Box 9, Folder 103)